<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Arm on Sergio Méndez Website</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/tags/arm/</link><description>Recent content in Arm on Sergio Méndez Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sergiops.xyz/tags/arm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Keynote: Boosting Cloud Native Efficiency and Performance with Arm Cloud Migration, KCD Antigua Guatemala 2025</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2025/keynote-arm-kcd-antigua-guatemala/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2025/keynote-arm-kcd-antigua-guatemala/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this Keynote Sergio Méndez will explain how Arm is helping user to migrate
into Arm microprocessors to deliver superior performance, multi cloud support, and get energy efficiency for all workloads and how this can impact
costs and performance when using cloud native environments.
Also Sergio will explain how Arm Cloud Migration resources can help companies to adopt Arm in their Kubernetes clusters (AKS, GKE, EKS) and in their applications using Java or .NET to reduce costs and improve efficiency in their workloads as a business strategy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This session happened in KCD Antigua Guatemala 2025, an official event from CNCF and sponsored by ARM and other sponsors.
&lt;a href="https://community.cncf.io/events/details/cncf-kcd-guatemala-presents-kcd-antigua-guatemala-2025/">Event&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Keynote: Cloud Native Technologies in Guatemala, KCD Antigua Guatemala 2025</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2025/keynote-cncgt-kcd-antigua-guatemala/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2025/keynote-cncgt-kcd-antigua-guatemala/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this session, Sergio Méndez tells us how Guatemala is evolving in cloud native technologies, both professionally and in academia. Along with data from the CNCF, this introductory session to the event will showcase analytics such as the importance of using these technologies in industry. And how countries like Guatemala can work both locally and export talent to work on systems that use cloud native technologies like Kubernetes. This session summarizes the state of the art of the use of Kubernetes and cloud native technologies in Guatemala.
&lt;a href="https://community.cncf.io/events/details/cncf-kcd-guatemala-presents-kcd-antigua-guatemala-2025/">Event&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Databases at the edge with K3s and ARM devices, Data on Kubernetes (DoK)</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2022/databases-edge-k3s-arm-dok/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2022/databases-edge-k3s-arm-dok/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this session, Sergio Méndez is going to share his experience and history behind why and what motivated him to write his book “Edge Computing with Kubernetes” by Packt publisher. After this introduction, he is going to give a walkthrough of the different chapters of the book explaining in a practical way how to use the content of each chapter to solve your day-to-day edge computing system problems and how to run your edge systems on ARM devices with the lightweight Kubernetes K3s.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/data-on-kubernetes-community/events/289963706/">Event Link&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sergioarmgpl/status/1597765873242034176">Photo&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1Np2liC2pTKINTbYDKtGaR2-6UJO3CgVI/edit?usp=sharing&amp;amp;ouid=117971317963904890005&amp;amp;rtpof=true&amp;amp;sd=true">Slides&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building a Multi-Node Cluster with K3s Using ARM Devices, Kubernetes on Edge Day EU 2022, KubeConEU Spain</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2022/multi-node-cluster-k3s-arm-k8s-edge-day-eu/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2022/multi-node-cluster-k3s-arm-k8s-edge-day-eu/</guid><description>&lt;p>Edge computing is coming as a way to improve user experience for applications, processing data near to the source. Sometimes in edge computing you share data between local machines and the cloud. If you are starting an edge computing project, you could be interested in taking advantage of containers on the edge. Here is where K3s shines to implement edge computing solutions on low resources environments that commonly use ARM devices. In this talk we are going to explore the key elements and best practices to build a K3s cluster on the edge using ARM devices. The talk will show how to build this cluster using Raspberry devices, showing how to configure your local network and a bare metal load balancer with MetalLB, and install other cloud native storage blocks such as Longhorn or OpenEBS. This to finally get a production ready K3s cluster. The talk also provides a quickstart to build edge computing environments for your needs, mentioning different use cases and challenges of this kind when building edge solutions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://sched.co/zsAc">Event Link&lt;/a> |
&lt;a href="https://b.link/EdgeDayK3sRPi2022">Slides&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>