<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>edgecomputing on Sergio Méndez Website</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/tags/edgecomputing/</link><description>Recent content in edgecomputing on Sergio Méndez Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sergiops.xyz/tags/edgecomputing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building Smart Farms with Edge Computing Systems Using Kubernetes, Open Source Summit Latam, Embedded IoT Summit</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2022/smart-farms-edge-k8s-oss-latam/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2022/smart-farms-edge-k8s-oss-latam/</guid><description>&lt;p>This talk presents how you can use K3s, a lightweight Kubernetes distribution to implement an edge computing system. This talk also presents different use case scenarios where you can use K3s, temperature and humidity sensors to start building a smart farm. During the talk the speaker will show the different layers of and edge computing systems and where are the different pieces of a smart farm located across these layers. At the end of this talk Sergio is going to show a basic weather monitoring system implemented using K3s and Raspberry Pi devices, temperature and humidity sensors, MySQL and Grafana, showing in real-time how to monitor plants in gardens or farms. This example represents the basis of complex smart farms use cases.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://sched.co/15Brb">Event Link&lt;/a> |
&lt;a href="https://b.link/EdgeDayK3sRPi2022">Slides&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Smart Farms systems using K3s a lightweight Kubernetes, OpenInfraDays México</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2022/smart-farms-k3s-k8s-openinfradays-mx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2022/smart-farms-k3s-k8s-openinfradays-mx/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this talk, Sergio Méndez shows us how Kubernetes can be used to monitor plants in gardens or farms using edge Kubernetes clusters in order to implement smart farm systems. This talk also presents a short demo, showing how you can monitor the temperature and humidity in a garden to take actions like watering plants. This demo runs using some basic sensors, K3s, a lightweight Kubernetes, and MySQL together with Grafana to show weather metrics of your garden or farm in real-time. During the talk, the attendee will learn how to implement a basic smart farm system using Kubernetes at the edge.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://eventee.co/en/e/open-infrastructure-days-mexico-2022-13797">Event Link&lt;/a> |
&lt;a href="https://b.link/SFK3sOIDMX2022">Slides&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building a Multi-Node Cluster with K3s Using ARM Devices, Kubernetes on Edge Day EU 2022, KubeConEU Spain</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2022/multi-node-cluster-k3s-arm-k8s-edge-day-eu/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2022/multi-node-cluster-k3s-arm-k8s-edge-day-eu/</guid><description>&lt;p>Edge computing is coming as a way to improve user experience for applications, processing data near to the source. Sometimes in edge computing you share data between local machines and the cloud. If you are starting an edge computing project, you could be interested in taking advantage of containers on the edge. Here is where K3s shines to implement edge computing solutions on low resources environments that commonly use ARM devices. In this talk we are going to explore the key elements and best practices to build a K3s cluster on the edge using ARM devices. The talk will show how to build this cluster using Raspberry devices, showing how to configure your local network and a bare metal load balancer with MetalLB, and install other cloud native storage blocks such as Longhorn or OpenEBS. This to finally get a production ready K3s cluster. The talk also provides a quickstart to build edge computing environments for your needs, mentioning different use cases and challenges of this kind when building edge solutions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://sched.co/zsAc">Event Link&lt;/a> |
&lt;a href="https://b.link/EdgeDayK3sRPi2022">Slides&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>