<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cncf on Sergio Méndez Website</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/tags/cncf/</link><description>Recent content in cncf on Sergio Méndez Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sergiops.xyz/tags/cncf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Despliegues en Edge con Flux, Cloud Native Guatemala</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2024/edge-deployments-flux-cloudnative-gt/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2024/edge-deployments-flux-cloudnative-gt/</guid><description>&lt;p>I spoke at Cloud Guatemala with the topic &amp;ldquo;Edge deployments with Flux&amp;rdquo; it was about how to take advantage of Flux at the edge to update devices. I also hosted the event with other organizers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://community.cncf.io/e/m6bh5c">Event&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/cloud-native-guatemala_cloudnative-kubernetes-kcdguatemala-activity-7166582840346808320-v4u6?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=member_desktop">LinkedIn Post&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/cloudnativegt/status/1762664467429540068">Photo 1&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A KCD lead by the next generation of cloud native engineers, Blog Post, cncf.io</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/contributions/kcd-students-next-generation-cncf/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/contributions/kcd-students-next-generation-cncf/</guid><description>&lt;p>We want to share this article with you on how San Carlos University students, technology enthusiasts and collaborators from the countryside had led Cloud Native events in Guatemala, showing how they are the next generation of Cloud Native engineers in our country. I participating leading this blog post for CNCF with my students, and also organizing the blog post about the content.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.cncf.io/blog/2024/02/02/a-kcd-lead-by-the-next-generation-of-cloud-native-engineers/">CNCF Link&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/cloud-native-guatemala_cloudnative-kubernetes-kcdguatemala-activity-7161154093682507776-708R?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=member_desktop">LinkedIn Post&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cooking a Sustainable Feijoada with Edge Cloud Native Technologies, KCD Sao Paulo, Brasil</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2024/edge-feijoada-kcd-sao-paulo-brasil/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2024/edge-feijoada-kcd-sao-paulo-brasil/</guid><description>&lt;p>I spoke at Cloud Guatemala with the topic &amp;ldquo;Edge deployments with Flux&amp;rdquo; it was about how to take advantage of Flux at the edge to update devices. I also hosted the event with other organizers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://community.cncf.io/events/details/cncf-kcd-brasil-presents-kcd-brasil-sao-paulo-2024/">Event&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/kcdsaopaulo_speakers-on-conhe%C3%A7a-o-palestrantesergio-activity-7160593917476847616-OvGJ?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=member_desktop">LinkedIn Post&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/sergioarmgpl_kubernetes-cloudnative-activity-7167363704685084672-cy-x?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=member_desktop">Photos&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TAG Env sustainability, Website translation into Spanish language, cncf.io</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/contributions/tag-env-sustainability-cngt-contribution/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/contributions/tag-env-sustainability-cngt-contribution/</guid><description>&lt;p>I participated leading this contribution and also adding my translation, to finally translate with all the Cloud Native Guatemala organizers the TAG Env Sustainability Website into Spanish.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://tag-env-sustainability.cncf.io/es/">TAG Env Sustainability Website ES Link&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/cncf-tag-environmental-sustainability_tag-environmental-sustainability-activity-7171505054883921921-YrTm?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=member_desktop">LinkedIn Post&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cloud Native para Humanos, Tech Community, Guatemala</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2024/cloudnative-for-humans-tech-community/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2024/cloudnative-for-humans-tech-community/</guid><description>&lt;p>I participated in the Tech Community Days, giving a quick introduction to CNCF and Kubernetes using drawings. I also covered topics as Service Meshes, certifications, env sustainability and also how to start contributing to CNCF projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/techcommunitygt_cncf-guatemala-activity-7157574195328008192-ntAV/">Video 1&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/techcommunitygt_faltan-solo-3-d%C3%ADas-para-el-tech-community-activity-7155997706912432128-M6k-?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=member_desktop">Banner&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/techcommunitygt_dos-grandes-profesionales-ahora-l%C3%ADderes-activity-7157588041484656641-DqYn?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=member_desktop">Photo 1&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/techcommunitygt_activity-7157574520826941440-TkUl?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=member_desktop">Photo 2&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Intro: Ecosistema CNCF, Cloud Native Guatemala, Online</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2024/intro-cncf-host-cloudnative-gt/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2024/intro-cncf-host-cloudnative-gt/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was host in the speaking session &amp;ldquo;Intro: Ecosistema CNCF&amp;rdquo;, I introduced the speaker and helped reading the questions in the session. Also in charge of the streaming. The topic was an introduction about CNCF.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://community.cncf.io/e/mb4anr/">Event&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Soccer World Cup with Multi Cluster with Kubernetes and Linkerd, USAC University, Alex Méndez, Jessica Botón, Christofer Borrayo, Yásmin Monterroso,Sergio Méndez, KCDSpain, online</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2022/usactar-multicluster-linkerd-kcdspain/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2022/usactar-multicluster-linkerd-kcdspain/</guid><description>&lt;p>Students of USAC Guatemala university, show how to use a Kubernetes multicluster configuration using Linkerd, gRPC, Kafka &amp;amp; React, to show stats in real-time about what the people comment of each soccer match.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://community.cncf.io/events/details/cncf-kcd-spain-presents-kcd-spain-2022/#agenda">Event Link&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/KCDSpain/status/1592586484137316353/photo/1">Photo&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="https://b.link/KCDSpainUSACTAR">Slides&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Serverless Functions at the Edge with Knative and K3s - Sergio Méndez, USAC University, KnativeConNA, Detroit</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2022/knative-k3s-knativecon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2022/knative-k3s-knativecon/</guid><description>&lt;p>Running code at edge could be challenging when running your programs using low power consumption devices. These devices often use ARM processors that match the low power consumption edge environments and have limited CPU and RAM to run your code. This talk is going to cover the basics of running serverless functions at the edge using Knative deployed at the edge in a light weight Kubernetes K3s. The demo of this session will show how to install Knative at the edge in a single node K3s cluster in a Raspberry Pi device as our edge device using an ARM processor. It also explained how this configuration can run your code in an efficient way managing endpoints for your code and concurrency using the internal envoy based proxy Contour that runs at the edge. At the end of the session we explain the pros and cons of running serverless functions at the edge and the challenges for development when using ARM devices, and how Knative with K3s can solve common edge computing use cases like smart farms, smart cities, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://sched.co/1AGbN">Event Link&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ClowderSpace/status/1584603806372753410">Photo&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="https://b.link/KnativeConNAK3s2022">Slides&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Students non code contributions for Linkerd and other CNCF projects, Sergio &amp; Flynn, Representing CNCF,CCOSS, México</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2022/non-code-students-contributions-ccoss/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2022/non-code-students-contributions-ccoss/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this talk we presented with Flynn from Buoyant and Linkerd community how students can contribute with and without code to the CNCF projects, in special how students are contributing to Linkerd.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://ccoss.org/sessions/2022/linkerd-guatemala">Event Link&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/i/broadcasts/1lDGLnEerAkxm">Video&lt;/a> |
&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1CGXHrIFf3jaziecWWlIEbidjxGArn3Wjeg6ZBHqozug/edit?usp=sharing">Slides&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Smart Traffic Systems with computer vision and Kubernetes at the edge, Coecys(Students summit), Guatemala, in person</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2022/smart-traffic-coecys/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2022/smart-traffic-coecys/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this talk, Sergio Méndez, professor at USAC University, presents how basic concepts of smart traffic systems and how to take advantage of the K3s a lightweight Kubernetes to build these kind of systems. This talk happened in the COECYS student summit from the USAC University.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/coecys/status/1569366166191198211">Event Link&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sergioarmgpl/status/1575903139496009729">Photo&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="https://b.link/coecys2022cvk3s">Slides&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting Involved Students Into the CNCF Cloud Native Ecosystem, Open Source Summit Latam, Community Leadership Conference</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2022/students-cncf-oss-latam/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2022/students-cncf-oss-latam/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this talk, Sergio Méndez, professor at USAC University, presents how he continuously updates his course content, to develop his students skills to work into the global tech market in the context of DevOps and cloud native technologies. Also he will present different strategies that he is using to update his content to introduce several CNCF open source projects such as Kubernetes as part of his course content, sharing the challenges of doing these changes. At the middle of the presentation, Sergio will share his experience hosting a Kubernetes Community Days in Guatemala with the participation of his students. Telling the audience in detail, how he organized this event, how he organized his students, speakers, the schedule, etc. At the end, Sergio presents the benefits that his students got when they participated in these events, and how now his students are participating in giving talks on local cloud native communities and events like KubeCon, applying for internships and getting jobs outside Guatemala.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://sched.co/15Bre">Event Link&lt;/a> |
&lt;a href="https://b.link/StudentsCNCFOSSLatam">Slides&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building Smart Farms with Edge Computing Systems Using Kubernetes, Open Source Summit Latam, Embedded IoT Summit</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2022/smart-farms-edge-k8s-oss-latam/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2022/smart-farms-edge-k8s-oss-latam/</guid><description>&lt;p>This talk presents how you can use K3s, a lightweight Kubernetes distribution to implement an edge computing system. This talk also presents different use case scenarios where you can use K3s, temperature and humidity sensors to start building a smart farm. During the talk the speaker will show the different layers of and edge computing systems and where are the different pieces of a smart farm located across these layers. At the end of this talk Sergio is going to show a basic weather monitoring system implemented using K3s and Raspberry Pi devices, temperature and humidity sensors, MySQL and Grafana, showing in real-time how to monitor plants in gardens or farms. This example represents the basis of complex smart farms use cases.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://sched.co/15Brb">Event Link&lt;/a> |
&lt;a href="https://b.link/EdgeDayK3sRPi2022">Slides&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cloud Native and CNCF Projects, CNCF Students. Guatemala/India</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2021/cncf-students-usac-cloudnative-projects/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2021/cncf-students-usac-cloudnative-projects/</guid><description>&lt;p>I hosted and speak in a live streaming for CNCF Students in Spanish, my students present the concepts of Cloud Native, CNCF projects, and how to start contributing. Online Event.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://community.cncf.io/events/details/cncf-cloud-native-students-presents-cloud-native-and-cncf-projects-cloud-native-y-proyectos-de-cncf/">Event Link&lt;/a> |&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Creating Containers with Containerd, CNCF Students. Guatemala</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2021/contained-cncf-students-guatemala/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2021/contained-cncf-students-guatemala/</guid><description>&lt;p>I hosted and speak in a live streaming for CNCF Students in Spanish, one of my students Leonel Aguilar presented a quick introduction to Containerd. Online Event.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://community.cncf.io/events/details/cncf-cloud-nativegt-presents-creando-containers-con-containerd/">Event Link&lt;/a> |&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cloud Native - Cloud Native Students Day URACCAN, Nicaragua</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2021/cloud-native-ni-students/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2021/cloud-native-ni-students/</guid><description>&lt;p>This talk was about Cloud Native, it explains the theory behind and how CNCF is involved in the state of art of Open Source projects in the context of cloud native. This talk was presented on Cloud Native Students Day URACCAN, Nicaragua. Online event.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://community.cncf.io/e/m6fd36">Event Link&lt;/a> |
&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1mnumqFyny2gJPrmWWANevJLb14QYBI_JciVQkaqXK2o/edit?usp=sharing">Slides&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Realtime COVID-19 Display System using Service Meshes, CNCF Students</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2021/cncf-students-usac-university-linkerd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2021/cncf-students-usac-university-linkerd/</guid><description>&lt;p>The students of USAC, university of Guatemala presented a project about a high concurrency system that displays real time information about Covid-19, this project used Cloud Native technologies such as Kubernetes, Linkerd, gRPC, Prometheus and others. Charles Pretzer from Linkerd Community and Field Engineer of Buoyant, helped us answering questions and promoted students to Join the Linkerd Community. This was one of many sessions that try to involve students into the CNCF ecosystems, we also promoted the hashtag #cncfstudents to share students work on the social networks, my role was to organize the event and help the students to present the project to the linkerd people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://community.cncf.io/events/details/cncf-cloud-nativegt-presents-realtime-covid-19-display-system-using-service-meshes/">Event Link&lt;/a> |
&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1qjy-FIRmFk0sjSVuAjJtKYuBrL3K2oMzNQZvKBfcic4/edit?usp=sharing">Slides&lt;/a>|
&lt;a href="https://github.com/sergioarmgpl/operating-systems-usac-course">Project Description&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How USAC university students use Linkerd in the Operating Systems course, Linkerd</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2020/linkerd-usac-community-meeting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2020/linkerd-usac-community-meeting/</guid><description>&lt;p>I shared with the Linkerd Community how we are experiment with Linkerd for the Operating Systems course in our final students project.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Minute: 37:40&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/Linkerd-Online-Community-Meetup/events/271761311">Linkerd Community Meetup Link&lt;/a>|
&lt;a href="https://github.com/sergioarmgpl/operating-systems-usac-course">Project Description&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>