<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cloudnative on Sergio Méndez Website</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/tags/cloudnative/</link><description>Recent content in cloudnative on Sergio Méndez Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sergiops.xyz/tags/cloudnative/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting Involved Students Into the CNCF Cloud Native Ecosystem, Open Source Summit Latam, Community Leadership Conference</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2022/students-cncf-oss-latam/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2022/students-cncf-oss-latam/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this talk, Sergio Méndez, professor at USAC University, presents how he continuously updates his course content, to develop his students skills to work into the global tech market in the context of DevOps and cloud native technologies. Also he will present different strategies that he is using to update his content to introduce several CNCF open source projects such as Kubernetes as part of his course content, sharing the challenges of doing these changes. At the middle of the presentation, Sergio will share his experience hosting a Kubernetes Community Days in Guatemala with the participation of his students. Telling the audience in detail, how he organized this event, how he organized his students, speakers, the schedule, etc. At the end, Sergio presents the benefits that his students got when they participated in these events, and how now his students are participating in giving talks on local cloud native communities and events like KubeCon, applying for internships and getting jobs outside Guatemala.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://sched.co/15Bre">Event Link&lt;/a> |
&lt;a href="https://b.link/StudentsCNCFOSSLatam">Slides&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building Smart Farms with Edge Computing Systems Using Kubernetes, Open Source Summit Latam, Embedded IoT Summit</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2022/smart-farms-edge-k8s-oss-latam/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2022/smart-farms-edge-k8s-oss-latam/</guid><description>&lt;p>This talk presents how you can use K3s, a lightweight Kubernetes distribution to implement an edge computing system. This talk also presents different use case scenarios where you can use K3s, temperature and humidity sensors to start building a smart farm. During the talk the speaker will show the different layers of and edge computing systems and where are the different pieces of a smart farm located across these layers. At the end of this talk Sergio is going to show a basic weather monitoring system implemented using K3s and Raspberry Pi devices, temperature and humidity sensors, MySQL and Grafana, showing in real-time how to monitor plants in gardens or farms. This example represents the basis of complex smart farms use cases.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://sched.co/15Brb">Event Link&lt;/a> |
&lt;a href="https://b.link/EdgeDayK3sRPi2022">Slides&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cloud Native and CNCF Projects, CNCF Students. Guatemala/India</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/community/2021/cncf-students-usac-cloudnative-projects/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/community/2021/cncf-students-usac-cloudnative-projects/</guid><description>&lt;p>I hosted and speak in a live streaming for CNCF Students in Spanish, my students present the concepts of Cloud Native, CNCF projects, and how to start contributing. Online Event.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://community.cncf.io/events/details/cncf-cloud-native-students-presents-cloud-native-and-cncf-projects-cloud-native-y-proyectos-de-cncf/">Event Link&lt;/a> |&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Creating Containers with Containerd, CNCF Students. Guatemala</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/community/2021/cncf-students-usac-cloudnative-projects-copy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/community/2021/cncf-students-usac-cloudnative-projects-copy/</guid><description>&lt;p>I hosted and speak in a live streaming for CNCF Students in Spanish, one of my students Leonel Aguilar presented a quick introduction to Containerd. Online Event.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://community.cncf.io/events/details/cncf-cloud-nativegt-presents-creando-containers-con-containerd/">Event Link&lt;/a> |&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cloud Native - Cloud Native Students Day URACCAN, Nicaragua</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2021/cloud-native-ni-students/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2021/cloud-native-ni-students/</guid><description>&lt;p>This talk was about Cloud Native, it explains the theory behind and how CNCF is involved in the state of art of Open Source projects in the context of cloud native. This talk was presented on Cloud Native Students Day URACCAN, Nicaragua. Online event.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://community.cncf.io/e/m6fd36">Event Link&lt;/a> |
&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1mnumqFyny2gJPrmWWANevJLb14QYBI_JciVQkaqXK2o/edit?usp=sharing">Slides&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>