<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>iot on Sergio Méndez Website</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/tags/iot/</link><description>Recent content in iot on Sergio Méndez Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sergiops.xyz/tags/iot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Monitoring weather at the edge with K3s and Raspberry Pi devices, Civo Navigate, Tampa, FL</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2023/foodtech-applications-kcdspain/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2023/foodtech-applications-kcdspain/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this talk Sergio Méndez will talk to us about how Agritech and Foodtech solutions running on the edge can help automate applications on farms that can help optimize processes in crops, fertilizer, or food generation, etc., and how these processes can generate an environment sustainable where the impact on the environment is reduced. Sergio will also explain how Agritech and Foodtech can revolutionize food production in Latin America, creating low-cost solutions, using K3s, a light Kubernetes and other cloud native technologies, accompanied by ARM hardware devices such as Raspberry Pi, for home projects. or productive use. At the end he will explain how Agritech and Foodtech are related to the TAG Environmental Sustainability, promoted in CNCF to have technological solutions that reduce the impact on the environment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://community.cncf.io/events/details/cncf-kcd-spain-presents-kcd-spain-2023/#agenda">Event Link&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cloud Native LATAM a year retrospective!, Cloud Native Latam, Online</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2023/cnlatam-retrospective-cnlatam/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2023/cnlatam-retrospective-cnlatam/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this talk, Sergio Méndez participated talking about the events that Cloud Native Guatemala Chapter hosted across the year, including a KCD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://community.cncf.io/e/mggtfc/">Event Link&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building Smart Farms with Edge Computing Systems Using Kubernetes, Kubernetes on Edge Day - Kubecon, Chicago</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2023/smart-farms-k8s-edge-day-kubecon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2023/smart-farms-k8s-edge-day-kubecon/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this talk Sergio presents different use case scenarios where people can use K3s(a lightweight Kubernetes) to implement an edge computing system that measures temperature and humidity sensors to build a smart farm. Smart farms have a lot of use cases in Latin American countries where agriculture is an important way for income. During the talk Sergio will explain how to design a basic smart farm system using the different edge computing layers to design this system. At the end of this talk Sergio is going to show a basic smart farm implementation using K3s and Raspberry Pi devices, temperature and humidity sensors, MySQL and Grafana, showing in real-time how to monitor plants in gardens or farms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://sched.co/1Rj2y">Event Schedule Link&lt;/a> |
&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1eMVnZPIXpt2XCiPokV45bIH5jb-HHC9j6URAIMgA-kU/edit?usp=sharing">Slides&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="https://github.com/sergioarmgpl/smart-farms-k8s-edge-day-2023">Repository&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sustainability Environments con ARM y Kubernetes, Cloud Native Guatemala, Online</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2023/sustainability-k8s-arm-cngt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2023/sustainability-k8s-arm-cngt/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this talk we will present the basic concepts of cloud native and how these technologies can impact better use of computing resources used in the cloud..&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://community.cncf.io/events/details/cncf-cloud-native-guatemala-presents-sustainability-week-green-kubernetes-cloud-native-guatemala/">Event Link&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Smart Farms con Kubernetes y LoRa, UVG University, Guatemala</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2023/smart-farms-arduino-day/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2023/smart-farms-arduino-day/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this talk, Sergio Méndez will showed to young univesity students how to use K3s and edge computing to build a smart farm system. This in person event was held at UVG university in Guatemala.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/tecsify_el-arduino-day-guatemala-uvg-fue-todo-un-activity-7064309566313766912-6_54/">Photos&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/tecsify_el-arduino-day-est%C3%A1-de-vuelta-esta-vez-activity-7062875897040629760-q3Pw/">Event Link&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="https://b.link/ArduinoGTK8sLoRa2023">Slides&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Monitoring weather at the edge with K3s and Raspberry Pi devices, Civo Navigate, Tampa, FL</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2023/monitoring-weather-k3s-civo-navigate/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2023/monitoring-weather-k3s-civo-navigate/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this talk, Sergio Méndez will show us how K3s (a lightweight Kubernetes) is used to create a small edge computing system that monitors temperature and humidity in real-time at the Civo Navigate event. During this talk, Sergio will show the different parts of this small edge computing system, including a short explanation of how MySQL, Grafana, and K3s are used and interact with each other to show this information in real-time, all this running on a small K3s cluster using Raspberry Pi devices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.civo.com/navigate/schedule">Event Schedule Link&lt;/a> |
&lt;a href="https://b.link/K3sWeatherCivoNavigate2023">Slides&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building Smart Farms with Edge Computing Systems Using Kubernetes, Open Source Summit Latam, Embedded IoT Summit</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2022/smart-farms-edge-k8s-oss-latam/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2022/smart-farms-edge-k8s-oss-latam/</guid><description>&lt;p>This talk presents how you can use K3s, a lightweight Kubernetes distribution to implement an edge computing system. This talk also presents different use case scenarios where you can use K3s, temperature and humidity sensors to start building a smart farm. During the talk the speaker will show the different layers of and edge computing systems and where are the different pieces of a smart farm located across these layers. At the end of this talk Sergio is going to show a basic weather monitoring system implemented using K3s and Raspberry Pi devices, temperature and humidity sensors, MySQL and Grafana, showing in real-time how to monitor plants in gardens or farms. This example represents the basis of complex smart farms use cases.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://sched.co/15Brb">Event Link&lt;/a> |
&lt;a href="https://b.link/EdgeDayK3sRPi2022">Slides&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>