<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>argocd on Sergio Méndez Website</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/tags/argocd/</link><description>Recent content in argocd on Sergio Méndez Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sergiops.xyz/tags/argocd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Quickstart with Internal Developer Platforms with ArgoCD and Github Actions, Cloud Native Amsterdam, Amsterdam</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2023/quickstart-gitops-argocd-cnamsterdam/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2023/quickstart-gitops-argocd-cnamsterdam/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this talk, Sergio Méndez is going to talk about Internal Developer Platforms (IDP), and all the concepts around IDPs and platform engineering, and how companies can start building IDPs using ArgoCD and Github Actions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During this talk, Sergio is going to show a small self-service implementation with ArgoCD to create Kubernetes applications using Github Actions forms to execute pipelines that create ArgoCD applications definitions that ArgoCD can use to provision applications in a Kubernetes cluster.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://community.cncf.io/events/details/cncf-amsterdam-presents-4-cloud-nativekubernetes-meetup-of-2023-hosted-by-mia-platform/">Event Link&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/sergioarmgpl_what-an-amazing-event-last-thursday-in-activity-7109545052762169344-lrJr/">LinkedIn Link&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Computer Vision at the Edge with K3s and Neural Network Accelerators, Civo Navigate Europe, London, UK</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2023/k3s-neural-networks-computer-vision-civo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2023/k3s-neural-networks-computer-vision-civo/</guid><description>&lt;p>Explore the world of edge computing and computer vision with Sergio Méndez. Learn how K3s and neural network accelerators are revolutionizing data processing at the edge. Discover AI and machine learning applications and master computer vision challenges in this informative talk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.civo.com/navigate">Event Link&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/sergioarmgpl_i-will-be-speaking-at-civo-navigate-this-activity-7099981668920225792-APsD">LinkedIn Link&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Merging To Main #6: The Journey to Self-Service GitOps, Codefresh, Online</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2023/self-service-argo-gitops-codefresh/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2023/self-service-argo-gitops-codefresh/</guid><description>&lt;p>Can you reduce your time spent enabling development teams without risking everything?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sergio Méndez, DevOps leader at Yalo and CNCF Ambassador joins this enlightening episode of Merging to Main and covers the trials and tribulations of creating the holy grail of DevOps, self-service GitOps.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Learn:
How do you structure teams responsibilities
Automate your permissions
Can you do self-service at the edge?
Where does an IDP or something like Backstage fit in?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://codefresh.io/events/merging-to-main-6-the-journey-to-self-service-gitops/">Event Link&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Internal developer platforms con ArgoCD y GitHub actions, KCD Colombia, Colombia, Medellín</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2023/idps-argocd-actions-kcdcolombia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2023/idps-argocd-actions-kcdcolombia/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this talk, Sergio Méndez explains how to create a self-service implementation to provision Kubernetes deployments by using ArgoCD and Github Actions. During this talk, Sergio presented how to use this tools to implement a basic Internal Developer Portal using ArgoCD and Github Actions with a short demonstration.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/kcd-colombia-2023-tickets-548105236517">Event Link 1&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/kcd-colombia_kcdcolombia2023-cncf-kcdguatemala-activity-7071183835190685696--Gho/">Event Link 2&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>