<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kafka on Sergio Méndez Website</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/tags/kafka/</link><description>Recent content in Kafka on Sergio Méndez Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sergiops.xyz/tags/kafka/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Usactar soccer world cup real time system con Linkerd y Kubernetes, KCD El Salvador, El Salvador</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2023/usactar-linkerd-k8s-kcdelsalvador/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2023/usactar-linkerd-k8s-kcdelsalvador/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this session, Sergio Méndez will demonstrate how students can learn about Service Meshes and cloud native technologies using Linkerd and Kubernetes at university. During this session, Sergio will show the USAC university project uses Linkerd for observability and multi-cluster interconnection. This real-time system called Usactar simulates comments and analytics of soccer matches based on the Qatar soccer cup. During the demo part, Sergio will show how the system works, how he observes Kafka message queues with gRPC interconnection and how he uses Linkerd for multi-cloud configuration to distribute components and data across different cloud providers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://community.cncf.io/events/details/cncf-kcd-el-salvador-presents-kcd-el-salvador-2023/">Event Link&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Usactar Soccer World Cup Real-Time System with Linkerd and Kubernetes, Cloud Native Now, virtual</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2023/usactar-real-time-linkerd-k8s-cloud-native-now/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2023/usactar-real-time-linkerd-k8s-cloud-native-now/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this session, Sergio Méndez demonstrates how students can learn about service meshes and cloud-native technologies using Linkerd in a university setting.
During the session, Sergio showcases a university project that used Linkerd for observability and multi-cluster interconnection. The real-time system simulates the comments and analytics for soccer matches in an event called Usactar based on the last World Cup in Qatar.
During the demonstration, Sergio will show how this system works, how to observe message queues in Kafka and how Linkerd uses a multi-cloud configuration to distribute components and data around different cloud providers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.techstrongevents.com/cloud-native-now-2023/speakers?page=1">Event Link&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Soccer World Cup with Multi Cluster with Kubernetes and Linkerd, USAC University, Alex Méndez, Jessica Botón, Christofer Borrayo, Yásmin Monterroso,Sergio Méndez, KCDSpain, online</title><link>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2022/usactar-multicluster-linkerd-kcdspain/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergiops.xyz/talks/2022/usactar-multicluster-linkerd-kcdspain/</guid><description>&lt;p>Students of USAC Guatemala university, show how to use a Kubernetes multicluster configuration using Linkerd, gRPC, Kafka &amp;amp; React, to show stats in real-time about what the people comment of each soccer match.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://community.cncf.io/events/details/cncf-kcd-spain-presents-kcd-spain-2022/#agenda">Event Link&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/KCDSpain/status/1592586484137316353/photo/1">Photo&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="https://b.link/KCDSpainUSACTAR">Slides&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>